[{"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339522", "question": "What silent film has been called the granddaddy of all Dracula movies?", "answer": "Nosferatu", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "6015f61ffe83fe1f2a824c1b", "question": "In 1919, 21 people were killed in Boston due to a flood of what?", "answer": "Molasses", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311338b33", "question": "What Greek god is the ruler of the underworld?", "answer": "Hades", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd5ede129f031133c919", "question": "What type of number has no factors other than 1 and itself?", "answer": "Prime", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5fefa55a6ce05a3942286ebf", "question": "What was Arnold Schwarzenegger's character's name in the film \"Total Recall\"?", "answer": "Dennis Quaid", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "6015f7a8fe83fe1f2a824c24", "question": "Who was the first woman to contest for the office of the President of the United States of America?", "answer": "In 1872, Victoria Woodhull became the first woman to run for the position of President of the United States.", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133ab7d", "question": "Freetown is the capital of which country?", "answer": "Sierra Leone", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5fe6990a20565ad31a57c73f", "question": "What legendary athlete lit the Olympic torch at the 1996 Atlanta Olympics?", "answer": "Mohammed Ali", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133c485", "question": "What is the name of the point of no return around the edge of a black hole?", "answer": "Event horizon", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b716", "question": "What is the Christmas dinner of choice for families in Burgundy, France?", "answer": "Turkey and chestnuts", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339601", "question": "Where does Julia Roberts go shopping in the 1990 movie \"Pretty Woman\"?", "answer": "Rodeo Drive", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f03113397f2", "question": "Who played the part of \"Bluebottle\" in a popular radio comedy series?", "answer": "Peter Sellers", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133ab03", "question": "In which US state is Mount Vernon?", "answer": "Virginia", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5921fcdca4edfd43a087adc3", "question": "What number is represented by \"V\" in Roman numerals?", "answer": "5", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133a7a7", "question": "What country borders only Brazil, Argentina, and the Atlantic Ocean?", "answer": "Uruguay", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f031133a170", "question": "Which band had a hit in 1983 with the song \"True\"?", "answer": "Spandau Ballet", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133be7e", "question": "In 2006, what quarterback became the last USFL veteran to play in an NFL game?", "answer": "Doug Flutie", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f031133a0cf", "question": "According to Elton John, what were we hopping and bopping to?", "answer": "Crocodile Rock", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133bc9f", "question": "What sport's lingo uses the term \"Fistmele\"?", "answer": "Archery", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5fe7c6f1877e98cb977789c5", "question": "Which East Asian country celebrates Golden Week?", "answer": "Japan", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133bf14", "question": "Who rode Shergar to victory in the Epsom Derby?", "answer": "Walter Swinburn", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339693", "question": "Who played the role of Catwoman in the 1992 movie \"Batman Returns\"?", "answer": "Michelle Pfeiffer", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5fe3ea2d38e4e5d4832e6313", "question": "What airline owned the 747 blown up by a terrorist bomb over Lockerbie, Scotland in 1988?", "answer": "PanAm", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5fe6a51d20565ad31a57c7c7", "question": "What President switched his Secret Service codename from \u201cTumbler\u201d?", "answer": "George W. Bush", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b1de", "question": "Which US president lived in Mount Vernon?", "answer": "George Washington", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133a4f6", "question": "St. Croix, St. John and St. Thomas are part of what US territory?", "answer": "Virgin Islands", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5a899b4160d398dc9cf7a69b", "question": "Egg Fu is the enemy of what superhero?", "answer": "Wonder Woman", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5fe7c7c8877e98cb977789d7", "question": "Which Mediterranean city has an area nicknamed \"The White City\"?", "answer": "Tel Aviv", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133c623", "question": "What is a nebula?", "answer": "A cloud of dust and gas", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5eb73d495e259d7869087334", "question": "In what year did the Kentucky Derby start?", "answer": "1875", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133bd88", "question": "What type of animal is the Japanese monster, Manda?", "answer": "Sea serpent", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5ab99adb21a8909e5c332d25", "question": "What is the Kelvin scale used to measure?", "answer": "Temperature", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f03113391a5", "question": "What is the name of Doc Brown's very clever dog in the \"Back to the Future\" movie franchise?", "answer": "Einstein", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f031133a0fc", "question": "Who created Gomez, Mortia and Uncle Fester as a cartoon?", "answer": "Charles Addams", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b05f", "question": "What famous Cherokee Indian created the alphabet for the Cherokee language?", "answer": "Sequoyah", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5feddbac6ce05a3942286d92", "question": "What does the yellow, red and blue stand for in the Steelers logo?", "answer": "Coal, Ore and Steel Scrap", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5fe4e3a206d333868d34d72e", "question": "During World War I, the territory known as South West Africa was a colony of which country?", "answer": "Germany", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133ae45", "question": "Of what nationality was the explorer Ponce de Leon?", "answer": "Spanish", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5fe8ef2401dd7bf43be5e7f2", "question": "Where was the candy apple invented?", "answer": "New Jersey", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133a7d7", "question": "Luzon and Mindanao are the two largest islands of what country?", "answer": "The Philippines", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133abf2", "question": "In what sort of landscape would you find an erg?", "answer": "Desert", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133a824", "question": "The Yalu River separates China from what other country?", "answer": "North Korea", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f03113397fd", "question": "Who was the only bare-footed Beatle on the Abbey Road album cover?", "answer": "Paul McCartney", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5ff20f0c31a458464a93c42d", "question": "What is the name of the fishing boat that is featured in the book \"The Perfect Storm\"?", "answer": "The Andrea Gail", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f031133957c", "question": "What won an Emmy for outstanding music direction in 1985?", "answer": "Christmas In Washington", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b5ec", "question": "Which TV production company brought the show \"Late Night With David Letterman\" to NBC?", "answer": "Worldwide Pants", "category": "general"}, {"id": "6015ec7ffe83fe1f2a824c03", "question": "Who in the New Testament got shipwrecked on one of his missionaries?", "answer": "Paul", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133a751", "question": "Which US state is nicknamed the \"Hawkeye State\"?", "answer": "Iowa", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b836", "question": "What is the diameter of a basketball hoop?", "answer": "18 inches", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133ad71", "question": "Who was nominated as the Democratic Party's presidential candidate for the 1968 US election?", "answer": "Hubert Humphrey", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133bc0b", "question": "Hockey legend Wayne Gretzky was born in what year?", "answer": "1961", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5febb8b07e83c707845b2135", "question": "Abraham Lincoln, Julius Caesar, Tutankhamen and Osama bin Laden all suffered from what disorder?", "answer": "Marfan syndrome", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5fe76c2beec85e375820b2cc", "question": "Which city is considered the perfume capital of the world?", "answer": "Grasse, France", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5fe93d236bd93ce3a4e5f6af", "question": "What is Jupiter's largest moon?", "answer": "Ganymede", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5fefbf206ce05a3942286efb", "question": "Who was the male lead in the film \"American Gigolo\"?", "answer": "Richard Gere", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5fffa74c73838c5c8a417f36", "question": "What is the fear of long words known as?", "answer": "Hippopotomostrosesquippedaliophobia", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339acd", "question": "What famous entertainer's tombstone reads, \"Everybody Loves Somebody Sometime\"?", "answer": "Dean Martin", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f03113393a2", "question": "Who plays Jullia Robert's best friend in the movie \"My Best Friend's Wedding\"?", "answer": "Dermot Mulroney", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5eb73c6b5e259d7869087331", "question": "Who was the designer of the Lincoln penny coin?", "answer": "Victor David Brenner", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b295", "question": "What day of the week was the initial October 24, 1929, crash that kicked off the Great Depression?", "answer": "Thursday", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339fb0", "question": "What film company's logo uses a lamp called Luxo, Jr. as the letter I?", "answer": "Pixar's", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5fec8da9ec223966ae8f8855", "question": "What was the first movie Sidney Poitier directed?", "answer": "\"Buck and the Preacher\"", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133ba5a", "question": "Where did Chicago Bears standout Brian Urlacher play college football?", "answer": "University of New Mexico", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5b3589855db0d66a186cb54c", "question": "The Republic of Benin shares a border with which other African country to the east?", "answer": "Nigeria", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133c16a", "question": "What is a Kissing gourami?", "answer": "Tropical fish", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5fd66230a5bfecdd737e0842", "question": "How many planets in our solar system have rings?", "answer": "4", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133c7ac", "question": "Ants belong to what family?", "answer": "Formicidae", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5fe7c423877e98cb9777899b", "question": "Which country features a man-made forest shaped into a guitar?", "answer": "Argentina", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311338d58", "question": "Who created the comic book character Wonder Woman?", "answer": "William Moulton Marston", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311338f69", "question": "What do the letters J and D stand for in J. D. Salinger's name?", "answer": "Jerome David", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "601b4b4f49076251badbeac2", "question": "The month of July was named after whom?", "answer": "Julius Caesar-- It was named by the Roman Senate in honor of the Roman general and statesman, it being the\u00a0month\u00a0of his birth.", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5fefc5666ce05a3942286f3d", "question": "The book \"I, Robot\" was written by whom?", "answer": "Isaac Asimov", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311339389", "question": "What is Indiana Jones' first name?", "answer": "Henry", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "6015ec33fe83fe1f2a824bfc", "question": "What was the name of the earliest form of paper currency?", "answer": "\"Flying Money\" -- used during China's Tang dynasty", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5fefa49c6ce05a3942286eb5", "question": "The Stay Puff Marshmallow Man originally appeared in which film?", "answer": "Ghostbusters", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5ae865ac7f28483af1e7fdd1", "question": "In 2018, a meme featured what Sonic character with a Ugandan accent saying: \"Do you know the way?\"", "answer": "Knuckles", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311339254", "question": "Who was the first character Johnny Depp portrayed in more than one movie?", "answer": "Jack Sparrow", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339f2d", "question": "Which band member of Blind Melon died of drug overdose?", "answer": "Shannon Hoon", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f031133a021", "question": "In the TV show \"Family Guy\", which member of the Griffin family is Herbert infatuated with?", "answer": "Chris", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339875", "question": "In Disney's \"The Jungle Book\", what kind of animal is Mowgli raised by?", "answer": "Wolves", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133bf03", "question": "What is the largest item on any menu in the world?", "answer": "Roasted camel", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f031133988b", "question": "Jello Biafra was the lead singer of what band?", "answer": "Dead Kennedys", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5fecdd4fec223966ae8f8904", "question": "Where was golf's Vijay Singh born?", "answer": "Fiji", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "6015f757fe83fe1f2a824c20", "question": "Which U.S. President worked as a tailor and made his own suits?", "answer": "Before he became President, Andrew Johnson worked as a tailor in Greeneville, Tennessee.", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b7a6", "question": "What color is the supposedly cursed Hope Diamond?", "answer": "Blue", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133bffd", "question": "Which famous artist designed the Chupa Chups logo in 1969?", "answer": "Salvador Dali", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133c2e5", "question": "What do fried spiders taste like?", "answer": "Nuts", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339b7b", "question": "In what Tom Cruise movie does his character play a doctor?", "answer": "Eyes Wide Shut", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f03113389d5", "question": "How old is Annie, according to the musical's script?", "answer": "11", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133aa33", "question": "What is the capital of the US state of Minnesota?", "answer": "Saint Paul", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd5ede129f031133c9ef", "question": "What mathematical symbol has the proper name of a Lemniscate?", "answer": "Infinity sign", "category": "science"}, {"id": "59220369a4edfd43a087ade2", "question": "Marzipan is made of which ground nut?", "answer": "Almond", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5fe7c298877e98cb9777898c", "question": "Who does Queen Elizabeth need permission from to enter the City of London?", "answer": "The Lord Mayor", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339d1a", "question": "What popular musician's last name is Kilcher?", "answer": "Jewel", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "6014c5cafbde8045e48466b0", "question": "A group of lizards is called what?", "answer": "Lounge -- Lounge lizard is also an early 1900s term that refers to a well-dressed man who works to seduce wealthy women in bars", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5fedd8b06ce05a3942286d73", "question": "The Soup Nazi was an infamous character on which sitcom?", "answer": "\"Seinfeld\"", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133a908", "question": "What major river runs through Boston?", "answer": "Charles", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133a2b0", "question": "What Canadian singer was married to Mutt Lange?", "answer": "Shania Twain", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5ede129f031133c871", "question": "What two elements make up water?", "answer": "Hydrogen and oxygen", "category": "science"}, {"id": "60173c3444491cbd7c5a17a4", "question": "What collectively-named languages evolved from Vulgar Latin?", "answer": "Romance or romanic language -- The five most spoken romance languages are Spanish, French, Portuguese, Italian and Romanian.", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b08d", "question": "The British passed the Intolerable Acts as punishment for what act by the American colonists?", "answer": "The Boston Tea Party", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133ae1d", "question": "Which country experienced a period called the Meiji Restoration?", "answer": "Japan", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5fef5d666ce05a3942286e2a", "question": "Which NFL teams always play on Thanksgiving Day?", "answer": "Detroit Lions and Dallas Cowboys", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133c22f", "question": "Which cartoon character has a girlfriend named Petunia?", "answer": "Porky Pig", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339bd9", "question": "What year was Mark Wahlberg born?", "answer": "1971", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133c464", "question": "What did Henry F. Phillips introduce for carpenters?", "answer": "Phillips crosshead screwdriver", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f03113391ab", "question": "Who does Emma Watson play in the Harry Potter films?", "answer": "Hermione", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339b36", "question": "What former talkshow host played Doug's sister, Stephanie, on \"The Kings of Queens\"?", "answer": "Ricki Lake", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5fecdc7eec223966ae8f88f8", "question": "Who plays Marty Byrde in the TV drama series \"Ozark?\"", "answer": "Jason Bateman", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5fe65f031f3c0ead6880d633", "question": "Which kind of bulbs were once exchanged as a form of currency?", "answer": "Tulips", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5bbd517c00d154d7af00b8d9", "question": "Puff Daddy's \"I'll Be Missing You\" was a tribute to which rapper?", "answer": "The Notorious B.I.G.", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd58de129f0311338911", "question": "What was the name of the cat in Walt Disney's movie \"Cinderella\"?", "answer": "Lucifer", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133af7c", "question": "The Battle of Lexington occurred at the start of what war?", "answer": "American Revolution", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f03113393ef", "question": "What actor was the executive producer of the mystery series \"Push, Nevada\"?", "answer": "Ben Affleck", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133ae4a", "question": "Who was the first US president to be assassinated?", "answer": "Abraham Lincoln", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b160", "question": "What title was Mother Teresa given by Pope John Paul II after her death?", "answer": "Blessed Teresa of Calcutta", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5c77cdd024f0f7a362efd543", "question": "Who was the captain of the Bonhomme Richard in the 18th Century??", "answer": "John Paul Jones", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5be580ed5415ba52ed6f0abb", "question": "Canada's Maple Leaf national flag was introduced under which Canadian Prime Minister?", "answer": "Lester B. Pearson", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5fe93a676bd93ce3a4e5f696", "question": "Stephen Hawking was a vigorous supporter of what interpretation of quantum mechanics?", "answer": "Many-worlds interpretation", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133a4eb", "question": "Which US state's name begins but doesn't end with the letter A?", "answer": "Arkansas", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "600f6e97a9e54d890926f6c7", "question": "Just off the coast of Venezuela, one will find Aruba, Bonaire, and Cura\u00e7ao, collectively known as what?", "answer": "The three islands are collectively known as the ABC Islands, or Dutch Antilles.", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133abf3", "question": "What major city lies on the River Torrens?", "answer": "Adelaide", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "58b370a31c3f17ccc40c8e16", "question": "Pubs are said to have evolved from what Anglo-Saxon establishment that started to appear in the 5th century?", "answer": "Alehouses", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133c02f", "question": "What type of food is Fontina?", "answer": "Cheese", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133bb7f", "question": "Who was the losing coach in the first Super Bowl, played January 15, 1967?", "answer": "Hank Stram", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133c14c", "question": "How is Samuel Langhorne Clemens better known?", "answer": "Mark Twain", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339abb", "question": "In the 1985 film \"Witness\", Harrison Ford's character goes undercover in what type of community?", "answer": "Amish", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5fe9f6c2ff048f679a45aade", "question": "What measures the amount of damage done by an earthquake?", "answer": "The Mercalli scale", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f03113397d7", "question": "Meg Ryan and Tom Hanks appeared together for the first time in which movie?", "answer": "Joe Versus the Volcano", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5fe90a3c01dd7bf43be5e898", "question": "An octopus can fit through any hole larger than its what?", "answer": "Its beak", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f031133925c", "question": "What French detective features in the \"Pink Panther\" movies?", "answer": "Jacques Clouseau", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133c544", "question": "What beam derives its name from \"light amplification by stimulated emission of radiation\"?", "answer": "Laser beam", "category": "science"}, {"id": "600f71d5a9e54d890926f6e6", "question": "What Texas National Park is larger than the state of Rhode Island?", "answer": "Big Bend National Park -- Established in 1935, it is located along the Rio Grande River in southern Texas\u2019s Chihuahuan Desert.", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5a25f1876682715b82711ce1", "question": "Pyrophobia is the fear of what?", "answer": "Fire", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133c2b2", "question": "What does LD50 stand for?", "answer": "Lethal Dose 50%, or Medium Lethal Dose", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133ad21", "question": "The Three Mile Island accident occurred in which US state?", "answer": "Pennsylvania", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5ede129f031133c87b", "question": "What animal is sometimes also called the \"glutton\"?", "answer": "The wolverine", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5fe7359deec85e375820b24e", "question": "Who said, \"Courage is what it takes to stand up and speak, it\u2019s also what it takes to sit down and listen.\"?", "answer": "Winston Churchill", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339562", "question": "In the movie It's a Wonderful Life, what did George dream of becoming?", "answer": "An architect", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311338e40", "question": "What's the only consonant sound that can end a word in Japanese?", "answer": "N", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133c75b", "question": "Dermatology studies which part of the human body?", "answer": "The skin", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f03113399e9", "question": "On what TV series did Katie Holmes first achieve stardom from 1998 to 2003?", "answer": "Dawson's Creek", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133a466", "question": "In what state would you find the Black Rock Desert?", "answer": "Nevada", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5de65a4cf89b9ec3da2d335e", "question": "Who played Bruce Wayne in the 1989 film \"Batman\"?", "answer": "Michael Keaton", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5ae863cc7f28483af1e7fdcc", "question": "How many territories does India have?", "answer": "7", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f03113399af", "question": "In the movie \"Basic Instinct\", Michael Douglas plays a cop in what city?", "answer": "San Francisco", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "58ab1a7bbaab681b09292194", "question": "What celebrity\u2019s car was fixed and raced in the 2009 documentary \u201cLove the Beast\u201d", "answer": "Eric Bana's", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f03113389d0", "question": "What nursery rhyme character was rich on Monday but broke on Sunday?", "answer": "Solomon Grundy", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5fe7c576877e98cb977789af", "question": "What is the least populous country in Africa?", "answer": "Seychelles", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5fc2f025cee580c7f8fd1e4a", "question": "What famous general was nicknamed \"Old blood and guts\" by his men?", "answer": "General George S. Patton", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311338d5b", "question": "What year saw the start of the \"Twilight\" book series?", "answer": "2005", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133aba4", "question": "What country is located immediately north of Sudan?", "answer": "Egypt", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b4de", "question": "What do you get when you mix bourbon, sugar, angostura bitters and water?", "answer": "An Old Fashioned", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b7eb", "question": "What does a chef do with a mandoline?", "answer": "Slice", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5fd669b1a5bfecdd737e087e", "question": "What is the ninth month of the Islamic calendar called?", "answer": "Ramadan", "category": "general"}, {"id": "58b370ea1c3f17ccc40c8e1a", "question": "A pub that is required to sell beer primarily from a single brewery is typically referred to as what?", "answer": "Tied house", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133a933", "question": "What is the only nation that shares a land border with Portugal?", "answer": "Spain", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "59decf04ea2747c8aff16d19", "question": "Which group recorded the albums \"Regatta de Blanc\" and \"Ghost in the Machine\"?", "answer": "The Police", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5fe771c8eec85e375820b2ff", "question": "What is New York's state bird?", "answer": "Bluebird", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd5ede129f031133c8fb", "question": "What is the leaf of a fern called?", "answer": "Frond", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133c4de", "question": "What fruit comes in Hass and Florida variety?", "answer": "Avocados", "category": "science"}, {"id": "6015e977fe83fe1f2a824be7", "question": "Who was the Confederate spy who became a bodyguard for the Pope at the Vatican?", "answer": "John Surratt", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339b54", "question": "Which cast member from the TV show \"Friends\" has a father who is a cast member on \"Days of Our Lives\"?", "answer": "Jennifer Aniston", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5fef92086ce05a3942286e7f", "question": "In what state did Bob Dillon grow up?", "answer": "Minnesota", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133a932", "question": "What is the only nation that shares a land border with Vatican City?", "answer": "Italy", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5fb08a71cf631c2414a13b60", "question": "What is singer Fergie\u2019s real name?", "answer": "Stacy Ann Ferguson", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5fe6581aae7e414034b5aee7", "question": "What year did Castro launch the revolution against Batista?", "answer": "1956", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133c2bc", "question": "What are the three main types of sugar?", "answer": "Glucose, fructose and sucrose", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd58de129f03113388ec", "question": "What is the technical name of the pound sign?", "answer": "Octothorpe", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5a4d990408b8581f80b092b2", "question": "What month in 2017 did North Korea fire a test missile across the Sea of Japan, prompting international condemnation?", "answer": "February", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5c3e99c4ebfabb9c85d8a975", "question": "Which modern musical instrument evolved from the \"Sackbut\"?", "answer": "The Trombone", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b3f5", "question": "What age preceded the Iron Age?", "answer": "The Bronze Age", "category": "history"}, {"id": "59a1a29312f2a7826b9b871d", "question": "What was the name of the first synthetic plastic ever developed?", "answer": "Bakelite", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311339365", "question": "30 Rock refers to what in the TV series \"30 Rock\"?", "answer": "30 Rockefeller Plaza", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339800", "question": "What label owns the rights to every Elvis recording ever made", "answer": "RCA", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133c54c", "question": "\"Consumption\" was the former name of what disease?", "answer": "Tuberculosis", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339993", "question": "What are the names of Rachael's two sisters on the TV show \"Friends\"?", "answer": "Amy and Jill", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f031133a14a", "question": "What was Walt Disney's middle name?", "answer": "Elias", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133bbc7", "question": "Capricorn is represented by what animal as its zodiacal symbol?", "answer": "Goat", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133bfa6", "question": "The King in chess can move a maximum of this many squares?", "answer": "Two", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133c745", "question": "In what organ of the human body is the hippocampus?", "answer": "The brain", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5ff14300b0ee8c595b6d39b0", "question": "With what type of quick drawings did a young Claude Monet begin creating art?", "answer": "Caricature", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b162", "question": "What organization was formed to replace \"The League of Nations\"?", "answer": "United Nations", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b855", "question": "What suspect in the standard game of Clue has the same name as a bird?", "answer": "Mrs. Peacock", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133be3b", "question": "How many players are there in a standard polo team?", "answer": "Four", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5ff214c731a458464a93c459", "question": "What is the scientific name of the plant used to make liquorice?", "answer": "Glycyrrhiza glabra", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133a5ff", "question": "What was Cape Kennedy renamed to in 1973?", "answer": "Cape Canaveral", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5bbc90ec60f0007efaba0e55", "question": "Dr. Jonathan Crane is the real name of which DC Comics supervillain?", "answer": "Scarecrow", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133c620", "question": "What is the chemical symbol for Carbon?", "answer": "C", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133bd5c", "question": "Which of the four biblical Gospels was written by an ex-tax collector?", "answer": "Matthew", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5a4d974f08b8581f80b092a9", "question": "What country was host to the \u201c2017 World Expo\u201d?", "answer": "Kazakhstan", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b9a0", "question": "What is the oldest marathon race in the US?", "answer": "Boston Marathon", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f031133a05b", "question": "What is the name of Amy Winehouse's first album?", "answer": "Frank", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133c234", "question": "What do Teal Pumpkins represent to Trick or Treaters?", "answer": "Non-Food Treats", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133a94f", "question": "What was the capital of Brazil until Brasilia was completed?", "answer": "Rio de Janeiro", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5fefc1176ce05a3942286f0e", "question": "In the Bourne film series, what is Jason Bourne's real name?", "answer": "David Webb", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133bdec", "question": "What was the first Major League Baseball team to play in a stadium with a fully retractable roof?", "answer": "The Toronto Blue Jays", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f031133a17a", "question": "Who released the 1970's album entitled \"Next\"?", "answer": "The Sensational Alex Harvey Band", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "58d06d3a870e6f05ba600857", "question": "Secretary birds are native to which continent?", "answer": "Africa", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133c131", "question": "In motor racing, what does a yellow flag mean?", "answer": "Caution", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5904a3b3cf93664eb10486bf", "question": "Who created the comic book series \"Strangers in Paradise\"?", "answer": "Terry Moore", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339de5", "question": "What code name does Linda Fiorentino receive at the end of the movie \"Men in Black\"?", "answer": "L", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133be85", "question": "For what mysterious figure is the latch on the inside of some Boeing passenger jet doors named?", "answer": "D. B. Cooper", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5fea4136ff048f679a45ab6e", "question": "What connects flower buds to the stem?", "answer": "Sepals", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5fe7c261877e98cb97778989", "question": "Where can you find an underwater volcano called \"Kick 'em Jenny\"?", "answer": "Caribbean Sea", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f031133925e", "question": "What country was the movie \"Full Metal Jacket\" filmed in?", "answer": "England", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "60078099bd51d85e222ab645", "question": "What art critic was influential in popularizing the work of Jackson Pollock?", "answer": "Clement Greenberg, a prominent art critic, is best remembered for his promotion of the abstract expressionist movement.", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "591c374c815febcc896f926f", "question": "Who wrote the detective novel \"The Maltese Falcon\"?", "answer": "Dashiell Hammett", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5c77cfb324f0f7a362efd54f", "question": "\"Green Arrow: Year One\" is a limited series published by who?", "answer": "DC Comics", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "594d05441a1c922dd1ac64a0", "question": "Which islands were the subject of a war between Argentina and United Kingdom in the 1980s?", "answer": "Falklands", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f03113392c8", "question": "Who authored the song \"In the Ghetto\"?", "answer": "Mac Davis", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd58de129f03113388f2", "question": "What note is the highest string of a violin usually tuned to?", "answer": "E", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311338e01", "question": "What is the Roman name of the Greek god Hypnos?", "answer": "Somnus", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "59f9b787364247bf200fb873", "question": "Which famous tapestry commemorates the Norman conquest of England?", "answer": "The Bayeux Tapestry", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133c3bd", "question": "What bird lays the smallest egg in relation to its size?", "answer": "Ostrich", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133c384", "question": "Wallace Carothers invented nylon while working as a scientist for what company?", "answer": "DuPont", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339cfa", "question": "In which movie did Christina Ricci portray a witch?", "answer": "Sleepy Hollow", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5fdc1758469bb8041d07a08f", "question": "What Spanish automobile manufacturer's first model was a three-wheeled two-door car?", "answer": "Kapi", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5fd81d35d0de9af39e9d468c", "question": "What is the largest pyramid?", "answer": "Pyramid of Cholula", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5fbaefd00738315b1fb74e33", "question": "Which is the longest English word without a vowel?", "answer": "Nymphly", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b2e5", "question": "What was the Allie's code name for the \"D-Day\" invasion of Normandy?", "answer": "Operation Overlord", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5febbcbf7e83c707845b2150", "question": "What is the name of the NFL's all-star exhibition game?", "answer": "Pro Bowl", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133a3de", "question": "What city is the capital of Turkey?", "answer": "Ankara", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133a1e7", "question": "Guitarist Dave Navarro was married for just over three years to which star of \"Baywatch\" and \"Singled Out\"?", "answer": "Carmen Electra", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133a5dc", "question": "What are the five boroughs of  New York City?", "answer": "Brooklyn, Queens, The Bronx, Manhattan and Staten Island", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd58de129f03113388e7", "question": "What is the longest one syllable word in the English language?", "answer": "Screeched", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133ab84", "question": "What is the second largest state in the US?", "answer": "Texas", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5fe77673eec85e375820b31b", "question": "Madagascar is located off the coast of what mainland country?", "answer": "Mozambique", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133c6b5", "question": "What was the last name of the US surveyor who invented the process for condensing milk in 1853?", "answer": "Gail Borden", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5909cd9fbb53d1af658864ea", "question": "What is Santa\u2019s postal code in Canada?", "answer": "H0H 0H0", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133c839", "question": "What is the primary ingredient in the silvery amalgam used in dental restoration?", "answer": "Mercury", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b0e0", "question": "During which war did the flag flying above Fort McHenry inspire Francis Scott Key's \"The Star-Spangled Banner\"?", "answer": "War of 1812", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339aca", "question": "On what TV show did the characters often hang out at the Warsaw Tavern?", "answer": "The Drew Carey Show", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "6015ffb5fe83fe1f2a824c4f", "question": "The term \"bonfire\" originated from which two Halloween related words?", "answer": "Bone and fire -- Bonfire is associated with ancient Celts where the bones of animals were burnt in order to fend off bad spirits.", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5fe4dd8306d333868d34d703", "question": "Eric the Red was a Viking from what period of time?", "answer": "900s", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f03113392e8", "question": "In the movie \"The Terminator\", what did the cyborg remove in order to repair itself?", "answer": "Its eyeball", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5f9f4511af848b908361b872", "question": "What colors are featured on the Chinese flag?", "answer": "Red and yellow.", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "6012195a63c99d48cd169af8", "question": "How many bricks were used to build the Empire State Building?", "answer": "10 million", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311338f64", "question": "What nationality was the sculptor Brancusi?", "answer": "Romanian", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5fea77f9ff048f679a45abd1", "question": "Which animal has a gestation period of only 12 to 14 days?", "answer": "Opossum", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5fe93d2c6bd93ce3a4e5f6b0", "question": "The conversion of ethanol to ethanoic acid is an example of what?", "answer": "Oxidation", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133aa16", "question": "What is the Capital of Guadeloupe?", "answer": "Basse-Terre", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311339261", "question": "Who had the fingers on his left hand glued together to make his disability look more real in the movie \"The Usual Suspects\"?", "answer": "Kevin Spacey", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b73b", "question": "Retsina is a wine traditionally made in which country?", "answer": "Greece", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133c56a", "question": "What chemical substance is the opposite of a base?", "answer": "Acid", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311338e7f", "question": "During what war was the novel \"Simplicissimus\" set?", "answer": "Thirty Years' War", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339769", "question": "In what city was the movie Chinatown filmed?", "answer": "Los Angeles", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133a68a", "question": "Lake Winnipesaukee is the largest lake in which US state?", "answer": "New Hampshire", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133af0b", "question": "During what century was the Mexican War fought?", "answer": "19th Century", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5ff7c28f2b316f4693fb67a1", "question": "Which candy company is known as the primary producer of \"conversation hearts\" in the United States?", "answer": "The New England Confectionary Company or NECCO", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5fc2f34dcee580c7f8fd1e55", "question": "Who said, \"I ain't got time to bleed.\"?", "answer": "Jesse Ventura", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5fea388bff048f679a45ab24", "question": "What scientist proposed the theory of continental drift?", "answer": "Alfred Wegener", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5e5f116ed274615ecf514539", "question": "What is the name of Olive Oyl\u2019s sister-in-law?", "answer": "Cylinda Oyl", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b4b6", "question": "Which war was said to be largely responsible for reviving Samuel Colt's firearms business?", "answer": "The Mexican-American War", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133c338", "question": "How fast, on average, do adult fingernails grow?", "answer": "3 millimeters per month", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133ba64", "question": "Which US city is home to the Second City Comedy Troupe?", "answer": "Chicago", "category": "general"}]